Shaza Ali

Cairo, Egypt



shaza.aly@gmail.com



+201062794773



linkedin.com/in/shazaali

Summary

I used to build Responsive functional web apps using:

HTML-CSS-JavaScript-JQuery -Bootstrap PHP-MySQL and Laravel, powerful OOP concepts.

During my Software Engineering Diploma in Faculty of Graduate Studies for Statistical Research, Cairo University, I gained powerful background about Relational Database, UML and Agile process.

Check my code in the following projects:

https://github.com/shazaaly

Experience



Technical Content Writer

Substack

Mar 2023 - Present (5 months)

Fullstack Javascript Instructor

GOMYCODE

Sep 2022 - Present (11 months)

Inspire students to learn today's in-demand technical and soft skills.

Coach students to independently find solutions to their problems.

Guide students in their learning path, encouraging them to learn by making.

Evaluate assignments and hold simulated job interviews.

Record video courses to optimize the students' learning experience.

Provide feedback on how we can improve!

Technical Support Web Developer

Salla E-Commerce Platform

Apr 2021 - Sep 2021 (6 months)

Ecommerce Developer

Freelance

Oct 2020 - Mar 2021 (6 months)



PHP Laravel Web Developer

Frealancer PHP Laravel

Feb 2018 - Mar 2021 (3 years 2 months)

Education

FGSSR - Faculty of Graduate Studies for Statistical Research at Cairo University

Professional Diploma, Computer Software Engineering 2018 - 2019

International Language Academy

Advanced English Conversation Course-American Accent 2014 - 2015

MODLI

English Conversation 2014 - 2014 English Conversation

Egyptian Syndicate Of Traiding

advanced course, stocks traiding 2010 - 2011 Stocks trading and technical analysis

EnglishScore

IELTS 2018 - Present

Senior Steps Training Center

Course, Full Stack Web Development 2019 - 2019

Cairo University

Bachelor's degree, Pharmacy Sep 2000 - Jun 2004 Pharmaceutical Sciences Bachelor Degree

⊗z™ Zero To Mastery Academy

Complete React Developer in 2022 (w/ Redux, Hooks, GraphQL)
Jun 2022 - Jul 2022

comprehensive online resource on React. This project based course will introduce you to all of the modern toolchain of a React developer in 2022. Along the way, we will build a massive e-commerce application similar to Shopify using React, Redux, React Hooks, React Suspense, React Router, GraphQL, Context API, Firebase, Redux-Saga, Stripe + more. This is going to be a full stack app (MERN stack), using Firebase.

Licenses & Certifications

- Programming Foundations: Fundamentals LinkedIn
- Programming Foundations: Beyond the Fundamentals LinkedIn
- in Programming Foundations: Object-Oriented Design LinkedIn
- in Programming Foundations: Data Structures LinkedIn
- rogramming Foundations: Algorithms LinkedIn
- in HTML Essential Training LinkedIn
- in CSS Essential Training LinkedIn
- in Programming Foundations: Software Testing/QA LinkedIn
- Programming Foundation: Databases LinkedIn AVTZYr-eB-OeJGUg-PhP5VXm5Fk5
- in Java Object-Oriented Programming LinkedIn
- Introduction to Front-End Development Coursera
 G7S8NZHA3F4P
- Programming with JavaScript Coursera e20231dcd40f6a00b24d34f92cee1161
- Version Control Coursera
 748F9K32BQL2
- React Basics Coursera
 6Y4RXR6B5PPQ
- Advanced React Coursera
 CQYYHENCG8DZ

Skills

React Hooks • styled-components • Database Design • JavaScript • JavaScript Libraries • JSON • JavaScript eXtension (JSX) • Vanilla JavaScript • Sass • Bootstrap